请你想象这样一堵墙：这堵墙从你目之所及的最右侧延伸到最左侧
I want you to imagine a wall. The wall stretches as far as you can see to the right and all the way off to the left.
墙比你高 你无法看见墙背后
It's taller than you, you can't see over it,
你知道墙的另一侧有很多很多人
and you know there are people on the other side, lots of people.
但你不清楚他们是否和你一样 不清楚他们是敌是友
But you just don't know if they're anything like you. Are they enemies or friends?
开发者创造代码 然后把代码扔过墙丢给运维
Developers created their code and threw it over the wall to operations,
之后发生的问题都是运维的责任了
and then it was operations' problem.
他们随心所欲 并不真正关心服务质量
Just doing whatever they feel like, not really caring about the quality of the service.
墙这两面的人几乎做着相反的工作
These two sides have almost opposing jobs -
一方做出改变 另一方尽可能抵制那些改变
one to make changes and one to resist those changes as much as possible.
但对于他们到底想共同达成什么 却没有在同一幅蓝图中规划过
But there's no talking on the same page about what it actually is they're trying to achieve.
我是 Saron Yitbarek 这里是《代码英雄》
I'm Saron Yitbarek and this is Command Line Heroes,
an original podcast from Red Hat.
由红帽公司推出的原创播客栏目
第四期 我们的标题是《DevOps 拆掉那堵墙》
Episode 4, DevOps, tear down that wall.
是的 数十年来 IT 界划分为各种角色
So yeah, for decades the IT world was defined by that division of roles.
一边是开发者 他们要尽可能快地去创造更多变化
You had developers on one side. They were incentivized to create as much change as quickly as possible.
然后另一边是运维团队
And then you had the operations team on the other side.
他们要去阻止太多改变发生
They were incentivized to prevent too much change from happening.
与此同时 代码在没有充分共鸣和沟通的条件下
In the meantime, code was getting tossed blindly over that wall，
被盲目扔过两方之间的墙
with no real empathy or communication between these two worlds
怎样才能拆掉这堵墙呢？这需要一个重大的转变
What would it take to tear down a wall like that? It would take a seismic shift.
上一期 我们看到了新的敏捷方法论 它重视不间断的迭代改进
Last episode, we saw how new a gile methodologies put a premium on constant iterative improvements
这当然是极好的
And that was great.
然而 这种变化也带来了未曾预料的后果
But with change, comes unintended consequences.
敏捷开发加快了软件更新迭代的速度
Agile increased the rate of changes we were making,
一夜之间 把代码丢到墙的另一端并默念上天保佑的这种做法
but then, suddenly, all that throwing code over the wall and hoping for the best
它的效率突然就跟不上新的开发方式了
it just wasn't fast enough anymore.
开发者和运维都将自己置于封闭、舒适的环境中
In our little silos, you were comfy with the way things were.
但人在封闭的环境中是无法高效地工作的
but siloed people can't get things done as fast as they should.
旧有的工作方式给我们限了速
We' d put a speed limit on ourselves,
因为开发者和运维未曾通力合作
because we weren't working together.
随着时间的推移 效率受限的弊端也越发明显 这是因为…
And that speed limit is getting to be more and more of a problem, because...
因为都是为了更快的将产品推向市场、提高敏捷性
It's all about faster time to market, increased agility
更多的迭代 而不是长期而大量的工作
doing more iterative, rather than longer - term big pieces of work.
Richard Henshall 是 Ansible 的一位产品经理
Richard Henshall is an Ansible product manager.
是的 还记得你以前下单购买服务器 四个月后到货
You know, I remember the days when you put in an order for a server and it turned up four months later.
所有东西都整合在一起 所以整个堆栈是一个整体
Everything was converged together, so that the entire stack was one thing
要花几年时间来设计和建造那些东西
and it took years for those to be designed and built.
现在这种情况已经不存在了 对于很多组织来说 这种方法已经…
That doesn't fly anymore and it's just disappeared, to the point that it is just…
已经寿终正寝 偶尔拿过来试试 然后放弃它
it’s up, try it, bring it back down again, for a lot of organizations.
如今 像亚马逊这样的公司每分钟都会部署几次新的代码
These days, a company like Amazon will deploy new code several times every minute.
想象一下 用按部就班的瀑布式工作流 简直不可能完成这些工作
Imagine trying to get that done using some step-by-step waterfall workflow. It's just impossible.
所以为了继续快速完成工作 那些关于稳定性、安全性、可靠性的顾虑
Soon enough, those ops concerns about stability, security, reliability,
为了跟上迭代的步伐 都会被运维丢到一边不管
will get pushed to the side in favor of moving fast.
同时 开发者也没有意识到他们的责任是创造真实环境可用的代码
Developers meanwhile didn't see it as their responsibility to produce code that worked in the real world.
开发者对稳定性和安全性毫无兴趣
Developers had little interest in stability and security issues,
但这些恰恰是我们需要解决的问题
but those are very real issues that we need to address.
所以 我们最终会有很多无谓的修改 在双方之间来来回回
So, we end up with a lot of needless revisions down the pipe, back and forth across the divide.
想象一下过度分工会如何拖慢公司效率
Think how much that division can slow a company down.
想象一下这样的效率会多低
Think how inefficient that could get.
但开发法者很少被鼓励思考除代码之外的其他事务
But developers were rarely encouraged to look beyond their own command line.
他们的目录规模只会越来越臃肿
The size of their directories would just grow and grow,
但他们从不清理
and they would never clean up,
除非已经无法工作才不得不清理
unless they wouldn't be able to get any work done without cleaning up.
Sandra Henry-Stocker 是位退休的系统管理员 为 IDG 杂志撰稿
Sandra Henry-Stocker is a retired sysadmin who writes for the IDG magazines.
我过去经常劝说别人 说 “嘿 你看 你用了这么多的磁盘空间
I was kind of often having a debate, saying, "Hey look, you're using this much disk space.
是不是有什么东西你可以整理一下
Isn't there something you can get rid of
这样我们就有更多的存储空间来运行了
so that we have more space to work,
因为服务器上的存储空间快用完了 ”是的 我们经常经历这些事
because we're running out of space on this server." And yeah, we'd go through that a lot.
归根结底 这是一个心态问题
Ultimately, this is a mindset problem.
这种开发者和运维之间的态度分裂
This divisive attitude between developers and operations,
一方不必去理解另一方的担忧
where one didn't have to understand the concerns of the other.
好吧 在过去这还没太大问题
Well, in the past that had been just fine,
但随着开发速度成为一种重要的优势 这种分裂的文化急需改进
but as speed became a premium that culture became more and more unstable.
孤立在自己的工作圈子里 效率太低了
Being siloed in your work bubble was just way too inefficient.
Jonah Horowitz 在 Stripe 的可靠性工程团队工作
Jonah Horowitz works for the Reliability Engineering team at Stripe.
他描述了即使开发人员和运维人员想一起工作
He describes how, even if developers and operations had wanted to work together,
他们也无法做到 因为从某种意义上说 他们被安排在对立的团队中
they couldn't have because in a sense they'd been placed on opposite teams
运维团队经常以正常运行时间和可靠性来衡量
The operations team is often measured by uptime and reliability,
而提高正常运行时间的最大方法之一
and one of the biggest ways to increase uptime is to decrease the amount of change in the system.
就是减少系统的变化量
当然 发布新功能就是在改变系统
But of course, releasing new features is changing the system,
而做产品工作的软件工程师有动力去尽快发布尽可能多的功能
and the software engineers who are doing product work
are incentivized to ship as many features as quickly as possible.
所以 当开发和运维的职责不同时 他们自然有了冲突
So you set up this conflict between dev and ops when you've got these separate roles.
开发者致力于新建功能 运营致力于维持运行
Developers committed to building features. Operations committed to keeping the site working.
两者目标相互矛盾
Two goals at odds with each other.
但就像我说的 由于对速度的需求越来越大
But like I said, because of the increasing need for speed,
对快速迭代发布的需求越来越大
for iterative rapid-fire releases,
开发和运维之间的脱节已经到了一个临界点
this disconnect between dev and ops was reaching a crisis point
必须要有所改变
and something had to give.
在 2009 年左右 将开发和运维分开的那堵墙看起来像是监狱的墙
Around 2009, the wall dividing dev and ops was looking a lot more like a prison wall than anything else.
我们需要的是一种新的方法论
What we needed was a new methodology
它能使开发和运维之间的隔阂顺畅过渡
that would smooth the transition from development to operations,
让双方以更快、更整体化的方式工作
allowing both sides to work in a faster, more holistic way.
视频平台 Small Town Heroes 的首席技术官 Patrick Debois
Patrick Debois, CTO of the video platform Small Town Heroes,
为想要拆掉这堵墙的人发起了一场会议
launched a conference for people who wanted to tear down that wall.
他把这个脑洞叫做 DevOps Days（开发运维日）
He called his brain child DevOps Days.
为了便利 他将其缩短为 DevOps 于是这场改革就有了名字
and thus the movement was given a name.
不过名字并不代表改革的一步
But a name is not a process,
我们知道为什么我们需要 DevOps 但究竟该如何做
it was clear why DevOps was needed, but how would it work?
我们应该如何将开发和运维结合起来而不引发战争
How are we supposed to bring dev and ops together without starting a war?
幸运的是 我有 Scott Hanselman 来指导我
Thankfully, I have Scott Hanselman to walk me through this.
Scott 是微软 .NET 和 ASP.NET 的首席项目经理
Scott's the principal program manager for .NET and ASP.NET at Microsoft.
所以 Scott 我认识你确实有几年了 但感觉还是相见恨晚啊
So Scott, I've known you for, I feel like I've known for forever, definitely a few years. (Forever. )
我想和你聊聊你如何成为一个开发者
I want to talk to you about the relationship between being a developer
和 DevOps 这些年的变化 觉得如何？
and what DevOps has looked like over the years. How does that sound?
嗯 听上去挺有意思
Yeah, that sounds like a plan.
好的 我认为究竟什么是 DevOps 是一个好的开场问题
Okay. So I think a good place to start is just defining what DevOps is.
你会怎么定义它呢？
How would you describe it?
在 2008 年 维基百科有个关于 DevOps 的定义确实很棒
The Wikipedia entry from 2008 that defines DevOps is actually very good.
它说 这是一套“惯例”
So, it's a set of practices
目的是在保证质量的前提下 缩短提交变更和变更投入生产之间的时间
that is intended to reduce the time
between committing a change
目的是在保证质量的前提下 缩短提交变更和变更投入生产之间的时间
and that change going into production while ensuring quality.
所以 如果你想想 假如今天是周二 我检查了一些代码
So if you think about, hey, I checked in some code.
而这些代码将在 6 月的版本中上线 这就很糟糕了
It's Tuesday and that will be going out in the June release. That sucks.
因为这不是持续集成 而是一年几次的集成
That would be not continuous integration. That would be a couple-of-times-a-year integration.
如果你有一个健康的 DevOps 体系
If you have a good healthy DevOps system,
如果你已经有“设置 – 上线(set – up)”的惯例
if you've done the set - up practices,
那么你就可以不断地将代码集成到生产中去
then you are going to be continuously integrating into production.
那么 你能做什么
So it's, what can you do?
你可以定义、创造怎样是最佳“惯例” 这将决定你能否成功
What best practices can you define, can you create, that will allow you to get it?
所以 我在周二检查的一些代码 周四就上线了
So, I checked in some code on Tuesday and it's in production on Thursday.
那么现在 为了保证高质量 最重要的事情就会是 - 谨慎上线
Now here's the important part—pause for effect—while ensuring high quality.
这个定义真的很有趣呢 是个“惯例”
So what's really interesting about that definition is it's a set of practices
但我觉得当我听人们谈论 DevOps 时 它具体一点
but I feel like when I hear people talk about DevOps , it's a little bit more crystallized, I guess
他们谈论它就像它是一个角色、一个工作、一个职位或一个头衔
They talk about it like it's a role, a job, a position, a title.
你觉得这与它是一套“惯例”的观点是否有冲突？
Does that conflict with the idea that it's a set of practices?
我认为 当一套新的方法或一个新的流行语出现时
I think that when a new set of practices or a new buzzword comes out,
人们喜欢把它加在名片上
people like to put it on a business card.
我不是不尊重那些正在收听这个播客
No disrespect to people who are listening to this podcast
并且感到被我冒犯、正把名片掏出来看的人们
and now are offended and looking at their business card and going,
“你开什么玩笑”
"This sucks."
虽然 他们现在可能正要怒盖笔电、退出这个播客
And now they're going to like, I don't know, slam their laptop shut, rage, quit this podcast.
有一个帖子写得非常好 作者是 Brian Guthrie
There was a really great thread by Brian Guthrie,
他是一个脑力劳动者 在 SoundCloud 工作
who is a thought worker, and he worked at SoundCloud.
他聊到过 DevOps
He talked about DevOps
他说 DevOps 就是一套惯例 不是什么别的
and he said that DevOps is a set of practices, period.
不是一个工作头衔、不是一个软件工具
It's not a job title. It's not a software tool.
不是一个你安装的东西、也不是一个团队的名字
It's not a thing you install. It's not a team name.
他的原话是：“DevOps 不是神奇的‘企业万能药’”
The way he phrased it was, "It's not magic enterprise fairy dust."
如果你没有好的惯例 如果你没有良好的习惯 你就没有 DevOps
If you don't have best practices, if you don't have good practices, you have no DevOps
所以 这更多的是一种心态 而不是摆出一个工作头衔 然后
So it's more a mindset than it is putting out a job title and like,
“我们要雇佣一个 DevOps 工程师
"We're going to a hire DevOps engineers
然后我们要把这些神奇的 DevOps 工程师撒到组织中”
and then we're going to sprinkle these magical DevOps engineers into the organization"
“虽然整个组织没有意志力 也没有信奉 DevOps 的想法 ”
"without the organization having organizational willpower and buying into the mindset that is DevOps ."
所以 如果你认为 DevOps 是一个工具或者是用来安装的东西
So, if you think it's a toolkit or a thing you install,
那么你就完全理解错了
then you've missed the point.
好吧 让我们回到过去 在 DevOps 这个名词出现之前
Okay, so let's go back in time, before DevOps was a term
在我们往名片上写 DevOps 或者把它作为一套“惯例”来讨论之前
before we had DevOps on our business cards or talked about it as a set of practices
在 10 年前 你会如何描述开发者和那些运维人员之间的关系？
10 years ago, how would you describe the relationship between developers
and those people who are on the ops side of things?
在 10 年前 你会如何描述开发者和那些运维人员之间的关系？
那是相当的水火不容
It was rather combative.
举个例子 运维控制着生产 但开发人员从来没有接近过生产
Like, the people in ops controlled production, and developers never got near production.
我们站在一堵不透明的墙的两侧
We were on different sides of a wall that was an opaque wall.
我们在进行开发的时候
We, over in development,
会尽可能地去模拟出生产环境
tried as much as we could to make something that looked like production,
但实际上从来没有…
but you never actually ...
那和生产环境总是相差甚远
it never looks like production.
我们有相当多问题
We had a couple of issues.
我们的开发环境从各个方面来说都不像生产环境
We had development environments that didn't look or feel or smell like production
所以你不可避免地会遇到那些
so inevitably you'd have those
“嘿 它在生产环境中的工作方式和在开发环境中的不同”的问题
Hey, it works different in production than it does in development," kind of environments
然后 从开发到投入生产之间的间距
And then, the distance between the check-in and when it got into production
是几周几周的长久间隔
was weeks and weeks and weeks
所以你的大脑甚至不在正确的频道上
so your brain wasn't even in the right headspace
比如说 我在一月份的时候就在研究这个功能 现在四月份才刚刚上线
Because I worked on that feature in January and it's just now rolling out in April
那么当 bug 不可避免地出现的时候
so then when the bug inevitably comes down,
要等到六月份才能修复 我甚至不记得我们之前在干嘛
it's not going to be fixed until June and I don't even remember what we were talking about
所以运维团队的人
So people in ops,
他们的工作几乎就是有意识地让我们慢下来
It was almost like their job was to consciously slow us down
好像他们的存在是为了让开发人员更慢
Like, they existed to make developers slower
然后他们还觉得我们随时会让生产环境崩坏
and then of course they felt that we wanted to break production at all times.
那么为什么会这样呢？
So why was it like that?
是对开发者想要做什么和他们做了什么不了解
Was it just a fundamental misunderstanding of what developers wanted and were trying to do?
还是信任问题？
Was it a trust issue?
为什么会有这么大的冲突？
Why was it so combative?
我觉得你已经回答了 而且回答得很到位
I think that you answered, you nailed that
你说的很对 确实是信任的问题
You answered it all correctly. There was a trust issue.
我觉得开发人员认为他们是特殊的
There was a sense I think that developers thought they were special
或者某些方面比 IT 人员更优越
or somehow better than IT people
而 IT 人员认为开发人员不尊重生产
and IT people thought that developers had no respect for production
我认为这种文化的产生 一部分来源于高层
I think that that culture came kind of from the top
他们认为我们是不同的组织 并且我们的目标也不同
the idea that we were different orgs and that somehow our goals were different
我认为软件业正在走向成熟
I think that there's some maturity that's happened in software
因为我们都意识到
where we all realized
无论业务是什么 我们写软件都是为了推动业务发展
that we write software in order to move the business forward, whatever that business is
所以现在有种 “我们都在往正确的方向推进” 的感觉
So that sense of, "We're all pushing in the right direction,"
但这是需要绝对的信任
But it was definitely trust,
可 DevOps 工程师不信任产品工程师来部署代码
because DevOps engineers don't trust product engineers to deploy
And no one understood the deployment process
没有人理解部署过程
人们只信任自己 他们的心态…
and people trusted only themselves, and they also ...
举个例子 就像“我只信任自己的工作”
Like, "I only trust myself to go into production."
“我不能相信 Saron 的工作
"I can't trust Saron to go into production,
她甚至不知道她在干些什么 我会做完所有的事情 ”
she doesn't know what she's talking about. I'll do it."
所以如果没有人真正理解这个系统
So if no one truly understood the system,
就像全栈工程师的概念 已经成为一个传说了
like the idea of a full stack engineer was a mythic thing
但是现在 我们开始将一整个组织称之为全栈
But now, we are starting to think about the whole stack as an organization
我们已经有了“全产品所有权”这样的名词
We've had terms like full product ownership
敏捷方法论也出现了 也就是说每个人都应该拥有产品
and the agile methodology has come along saying that everyone should own the product
社区对于软件所有权和对于代码的想法都慢慢发生了变化
and that sense of community ownership and community around the code all slowly changed
这种改变带来了一个充满信任的环境
changes things to bring an environment of trust
我是 Saron Yitbarek 你现在收听的是《代码英雄》
I'm Saron Yitbarek and you're listening to Command Line Heroes,
来自红帽公司的一档原创播客栏目
an original podcast from Red Hat
所以 要想让 DevOps 发挥出它的潜力
So, for DevOps to hit its potential
我们就需要双方更加信任彼此
we were going to need a lot of trust on both sides
这就意味着要有更多的沟通
and that means a lot more communication
回到 Richard Henshall 身上
Back to Richard Henshall
他认为双方的共情是 DevOps 的基石
He sees empathy for both sides as the cornerstone of DevOps
一些 DevOps 的从业者 一群真正优秀的从业者 都参与过这两种角色
Some of the DevOps practitioners, some of the really good ones, have done both roles
我认为这才是真正的力量所在
I think that is where the real power comes
当人们真正做过了两种角色 而不是只看到其中一种
is when people actually get to do both roles, rather than just seeing the other side
所以 你不该保持孤立 你实际上…
So you don't keep the separation, you're actually...
你应该去和双方都一起工作一段时间
You go and live in their shoes for a period of time.
我想这才是让人恢复同理心的方法
I think that's what brings the empathy back
现在 这不仅仅是为了温情的沟通
Now this isn't just communication for the sake of warm fuzzies.
Richard Henshall 所描述的是行业重点的转向 - Scott 刚刚提到过
What Richard Henshall is describing is the industry swerving toward that focus Scott mentioned.
一个关于持续集成的观点
A focus on continuous integration
软件不仅要以小批量快速编写和发布
Software was going to be, not just written and released in small rapid-fire batches
还要以小批量进行快速测试
but also tested in small rapid-fire batches
这意味着 开发人员需要得到即时反馈
And that meant, developers needed instant feedback
不管是对于他们正在编写的代码 还是代码在现实世界中的表现
on the code they were writing, and how it would perform in the real world
随着上市时间从几个月缩短到几天 再到几个小时
As time to market shrank from months to days, to hours
我们四处寻找一套新的工具 可以将任何可以自动化的元素自动化
we cast around for a new set of tools that could automate any element that could be automated.
你需要一个全新的生态系统和工具
You really need a whole new ecosystem of tooling
来最有效地进行
DevOpsto do DevOps most effectively
Gordon Haff 是一位红帽公司高级工程师
Gordon Haff is a senior manager at Red Hat.
我们看到有很多巨大的、DevOps 可以利用的新种集合工具和平台
What we see is this huge collection of new types of tooling and platforms that DevOps can make use of.
它们都诞生于开源
They're really all coming out of open source.
Gordon 是对的
Gordon's right
新的集合工具是很庞大
The collection of new tools is huge
关于开源这点他说的也对
and he's right about the open source angle too
在一个严格的专有系统中 自动化工具是不可能发展的
The growth of automation tools never would have been possible in a strictly proprietary system
其中有很多监控工具
Lot of monitoring tools out there
Prometheus 是其中一个常见的工具
Prometheus is a common one
它开始引起很多人兴趣 用于编排服务的 STO 也出自这里
STO for service orchestration is starting to interest a lot of people, so that's out there
GitHub 让你跟踪变化
GitHub let's you track changes
PagerDuty 管理数字业务
PagerDuty manages digital operations
NFS 可以跨网络挂载文件系统
NFS mounts file systems across a network
Jenkins 让你自动测试你的构建
Jenkins lets you automate testing on your build
这么多工具 这么多自动化流程
So many tools, so much automation
最终的结果是 开发人员可以将他们的变更直接推送到生产现场
The end result, developers can push their changes live
自动创建构造 实行经过严格管理的编译与针对性的自动测试
the build is automatically created, compilation is managed, and automated tests are run against it
Sandra Henry-Stocker 描述了这是怎样的变化
Sandra Henry-Stocker describes what a change this made
所以 我可以把我正在工作编写的东西快速部署
So I could take something that I was working on and rapidly deploy it
我可以只在一个系统上 通过命令行控制许多系统
and I could control many systems just from the command line on one
而不是必须在在很多不同的系统上工作
rather than having to work at a lot of different places
也不用学习就可以利用网络 将代码部署到其他机器上
or wonder how I was going to get something that I was working on
sent across a network and deployed on a lot of different machines.
现在 在计算机系统中进行改动更容易了
It became easier to basically sit in one spot
坐在一个地方 就能实行一切操作
and yet make my changes across a wide range of computer systems
自动化工具已经解决了速度问题
Automation tools had solved the speed problem
但我不希望我们只赞美工具 而忽略了实际的方法论
But I don't want us to just praise tools at the expense of the actual methodology
Scott Hanselman 和我谈到了这个微妙的界限
Scott Hanselman and I talked about that fine line
你在这次谈话开始时说 DevOps 是一套惯例
You started this conversation by saying DevOps is a set of practices,
是一种心态 是一种思维方式
it's a mindset, it's a way of thinking
听起来 我们创造的工具是我们应该思考和操作方式的具体代码实现
It sounds like the tools that we created are the manifestation,
the code version of the way we should be thinking and we should be operating.
我喜欢这句话 你真是个天才
I love that, you're a genius
没错 以前 我们的项目组长在 Word 文档中
Exactly. We used to have the product owners write in these Word documents
写下这些代码是如何工作的
about how the code should work
他们写的是规范 对吧?
They write the spec, right?
这些文档过期了吗？
When was the last time a Word document broke the build?
好吧 我只是很高兴 Scott 刚才说我是天才
Okay, partly I just wanted you to hear Scott calling me a genius
但我也确实认为 这些工具几乎是我们文化转变的象征
But I do think those tools are almost like symbols of our cultural shift
它们鼓励我们拓宽我们的角色定义
They encourage us to broaden our roles
我们开发者已经被迫
We developers have been forced to look
至少偶尔关注代码的运行
at least occasionally, from the command line
这样一来 开发和运维的主要职责就部分统一了
That way the priorities of dev and ops partly come into alignment
事实上 DevOps 的兴起告诉我们的是 在一个速度不断提升的世界里
In fact, what the rise of DevOps has made clear is that in a world of ever-increasing speed
没有人能够保持孤岛状态
nobody can afford to remain siloed
Jonah Horowitz 曾在湾区多家公司工作
Jonah Horowitz has worked for a number of Bay-area companies
包括 Quantcast 和 Netflix
including Quantcast and Netflix
他说即使是世界上一些最大的公司
He explains how even some of the largest companies in the world
也从这个角度重新塑造了他们的文化
have re-imagined their culture in this light.
我们在文化上得到了整个公司的认同 就像
We had sort of this cultural buy-in from the entire company, that was like
“这就是我们要部署软件的方式”
"This is how we're going to deploy software"
“我们将以小批量的方式进行部署:”
"We're going to do it in these small batches"
"我们将使用这些程序帮助部署 ”
"We're going to do it using these deployment procedures."
如果这只是运维团队的行动 我不认为它可以成功
I don't think it can be successful if it's just being driven by the ops team.
这必须成为公司的管理层和领导层所认同的东西才能发挥作用
It has to be something that the management and leadership at the company buy into
而这件事很大程度上 意味着一种文化转变
It's very much a cultural shift
当 MacKenzie 对 800 名 CIO 和 IT 高管进行调查时
When MacKenzie surveyed 800 CIOs and IT executives
80% 的人表示 他们正在规划让自己的一部分下属组织实施 DevOps
80% said they were implementing DevOps in some part of their organization
超过一半的人计划到 2020 年在全公司范围内实施
and more than half planned to implement it company-wide by 2020
高管们意识到 自动化工具可以提升交付速度
Executives are realizing that automation tools ramp up the speed of delivery.
这些人过去也是这样的人 他们习惯于让一个货板先到达数据中心
These are the same people who used to be okay with having a pallet arrive in a datacenter
然后在新机器上线之前让它在那里放上整整一个月
and then have it sit there for a whole month before a new machine was brought online
不过在今天 如果你等待的时间超过 10 分钟
Today, if you're waiting longer than 10 minutes to have something provisioned
就说明你做错了什么
you're doing something wrong
随着竞争对手的速度增加 没有人能够承受得起落后
With competitors hitting speeds like that, nobody can afford to be left behind.
我可以想象 运维团队一定很紧张
I can imagine that ops teams must have been nervous
因为他们把所有的工具都交给开发人员
handing all those tools over to developers
运维团队习惯了做成年人
Ops was used to being the grownup
而现在叫他们把车钥匙交给一贯的孩子 - 开发人员？
and now they were supposed to hand over the keys to the car?
呀 我想我们开发人员正在学习 如何在不破坏东西的前提下快速移动
Yikes. I think we developers are learning to move fast without breaking things.
但随着 DevOps 革命的尘埃落定
But as the dust settles on the DevOps revolution
变化最大的可能是运维团队
the biggest changes may be for the ops team
DevOps 是否真的威胁到了运维的存在？
Does DevOps actually threaten the role of operations?
开发是否在用它闪亮的新工具来吃掉运维？
Is dev using its shiny new tools to eat ops?
Cindy Sridharan 是一位开发者
Cindy Sridharan is a developer
她写了一篇长篇调查文章来讨论这些问题
who wrote a long investigative piece about all this
在你的文章和博客中
In your article and your blog post, you mentioned that
你提到运维人员对事情这样的发展并不一定满意
operations people were not necessarily happy with the way things were going
到底发生了什么？你会说什么？
What was going on? What would you say?
这么说吧 DevOps 的理想是责任共享
Let's put it this way, the DevOps ideal was that responsibilities will be shared
开发者和运维将有 就像你知道的 更多的是五五分成
That developers and operations would have, like you know, more of a 50-50 split
以真正确保软件的整体交付
for really ensuring the holistic delivery of software.
我认为很多运维工程师的不快乐源于这样一个事实
I think a lot of the unhappiness from engineers, from operations engineers
那就是这些改变都没有实际功效
stems from the fact that that is not really the reality on the ground
他们仍然是总被鸡蛋挑骨头的人
and that they're still the ones who are always picking the short straw
他们仍然是总做苦力工作的那些人
They're still the ones who are sort like always doing the grunt work
他们还是那些主要肩负着实际运行应用的责任的人
They're still the ones who are primarily shouldering responsibility for actually running the applications
而开发者不一定要做得足够好
and the developers aren't necessarily doing enough
这个问题在未来几年将至关重要
The question will be a crucial one over the next few years
DevOps 的作用到底有多大?
how opsy is DevOps going to be?
随着我们的自动化进程 运维的作用是会被削弱 还是会发生转变？
As we automate, does the role of ops get diminished, or does it transform?
或许旧项目的维护会被自动化
Maybe the responsibility of older Ops will get automated,
如此 他们的运维团队就能协助新服务的开发
so their teams can focus on creating new services,
而不用受困于原本的项目
Instead of just maintaining old ones.
无论如何 可以确信 运维的工作也在演化
However, the Ops' role evolves. This much is clear.
这种方法论实际上是在塑造技术
The DevOps methodology is actually shaping the tech
反过来技术也在塑造方法论
and in turn the tech is shaping the methodology
这样就有了一个神奇的反馈循环
There's this amazing feedback loop
文化造就了工具 而工具又强化了文化
Culture makes the tools, and the tools reinforce the culture.
最后 我们在节目开头描述的那堵墙
In the end, that wall we described at the top of the episode,
也就是把开发和运维划分开来的那堵墙
the one dividing dev from ops
我甚至不知道“把你的代码扔过墙”的比喻
I don't even know if the whole throw - your - code - over - the - wall analogy
在五年后对一个开发者来说是否有意义
is going to make sense to a developer in five years
如果五年后大家都听不懂这个比喻 那真是一件大好事
and that's sort of a great thing
不过目前为止的访谈很有价值 我听到了很多新的故事
Already, when I talk to folks today, I'm hearing a new story
现在说话的是云架构师 Richard Henshall
Cloud architect Richard Henshall
我觉得 DevOps 开始让人们意识到对方关心的是什么
I think it is starting to make people realize what the other side of the equation was concerned about more
我看到了更多对彼此的理解
I've seen a lot more understanding.
现在是系统管理员 Jonah Horowitz
Sysadmin Jonah Horowitz
我认为你需要很棒的技巧来写出真正好的软件
I think there's a craft to writing really good software
我在与我合作过最棒的开发者身上看到了一件事
and one thing that I see in the best developers that I work with
那就是他们真的 他们贡献了软件工程的新技巧
is that they really, they push the craft of software engineering
或者说他们推动了软件开发这个行业的发展
or software development, forward.
最后一个是系统管理员 Sandra Henry-Stocker
Sysadmin, Sandra Henry-Stocker
我认为 开发者会变得更加精明、更加谨慎
I think that developers are becoming much more astute and much more careful
他们始终要提升自己的技能
They're consistently having to up their skills
我知道这需要很多辛苦的学习
and I know that takes a lot of work
DevOps 是个爱的结晶
It's a love-in
原来 在那堵墙的另一边还有一些朋友
Turns out, there were some friends on the other side of that wall
很高兴认识你们
Nice to meet you
所以 坦白一下 我以前总觉得 DevOps 很无聊
So, a confession, I always used to think DevOps was boring
就是一堆硬核的自动化脚本和扩展问题
just a bunch of hardcore automation scripts and scaling issues
我的抵触情绪有一部分是出于它的实践难度
My resistance was partly just practical
作为开发者 我每周都要面对一些新出来的工具 一些新的框架
As developers, every week there's some new tool coming out, some new framework
DevOps 一直是那些可怕的、快速变化的一部分
DevOps has been part of those scary, fast changes
但现在 尤其是听了这些故事之后 我明白了
But now, especially after hearing these stories, I get it
DevOps 不仅仅是其工具
DevOps is more than its tools
它是教导我们如何合作 更快地构建更好的产品的方法
It's how we can work together to build better products faster
好消息是 随着为你我这样的开发者准备的新平台出现
Here's the good news, as we develop new platforms for developers like you and me
我们的工作变得更好、更快、更能适应不同的环境
my work is becoming better, faster, and more adaptive to different environments
我的业务圈也可以不断扩大
The circle of interest can keep expanding too
你会看到人们将 DevOps 扩大到安全领域
You see people widening DevOps to include security,
所以我们能得到 Sec DevOps
so we get Sec DevOps
或者他们开始包含商务 那我们就得到了 Biz DevOps
or they include business, so we get Biz DevOps
我们现在要辩论的话题是：
The debate we're going to have now is
对于一个开发者来说 不仅要了解如何使用这些工具
how important is it for a developer to understand not just how to use these tools
还有了解所有 DevOps 的东西是如何工作的必要吗？
but how all that DevOps stuff even works
以及我们需要所有开发者都去了解这个新世界吗？
and how realistic is it to expect developers to understand that new world?
这场辩论的结果将决定未来一期《代码英雄》的内容
The way we settle that debate is going to define the work of tomorrow's Command Line Heroes.
你可能已经注意到 在所有关于工具和自动化的谈话中
You might have noticed that in all that talk about tools and automation
我漏掉了一些工具
I left out some big ones
好吧 我把这些留到下一期
Well, I'm saving those for next time
当所有这些 DevOps 自动化达到光速时 我们将追踪容器的崛起
when all this DevOps automation hits lightspeed and we track the rise of containers
是的 这些都会留到第五期
It's all in episode 5
《代码英雄》是红帽公司推出的原创播客栏目
Command Line Heroes is an original podcast from Red Hat
想要了解更多关于本期节目和以往节目的信息
For more information about this and past episodes,
请访问 redhat.com/commandlineheroes
go to redhat.com/commandlineheroes
在那里 你还可以注册我们的新闻资讯
Once you're there, you can also sign up for our newsletter
想免费获得新剧集的自动推送 请务必订阅该节目
and to get new episodes delivered automatically for free, make sure to subscribe to the show
只要在苹果播客、Spotify、
Just search for Command Line Heroes in Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
Google Play、CastBox 等平台中搜索《代码英雄》
Google Play, CastBox,
或者通过其他方式收听
or however you get your podcasts.
并点击订阅 这样你就能在第一时间知道最新剧集
hen hit subscribe, so you'll be the first to know when new episodes are available
我是 Saron Yitbarek 感谢您的收听 编程不止
I'm Saron Yitbarek. Thanks for listening, and keep on coding